<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Peter Dickinson Books</title>
    <link>http://peterdickinson.com/categories/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Peter Dickinson Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://peterdickinson.com/categories/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One Foot in the Grave</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/onefoot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/onefoot/</guid>
      <description>About the book A coda to the Pibble series. Pibble is in a nursing home, prematurely feeble and despairing. To put an end to it by dying of hypothermia, he slips out one bitter winter&amp;rsquo;s night and climbs to the top of the water tower, only to find that the place he had chosen is already occupied by the dead body of another. Duty drives him to return and report it, and then, inexorably, he finds himself forced to unravel, from his sick-bed and through the come-and-go of delirium, what happened, and why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep and His Brother</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sleepandbrother/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sleepandbrother/</guid>
      <description>About the book Pibble, retired, involves himself in home for children suffering from rare disease (symptoms before early death include apparent telepathic powers), lavishly funded for ESP research by Greek tycoon. There&amp;rsquo;s an apparently accidental death in a fire, which Pibble noses into.
Reviews  Brilliantly original, as always. Times Literary Supplement  An excellently engineered story. H.R. F. Keating, The Times  The writing, as always, has style, and the setting…is full of invention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Glass-Sided Ants’ Nest (Skin Deep)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/the-glass-sided-ants-nest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/the-glass-sided-ants-nest/</guid>
      <description>About the book Set in Notting Dale, West London; remnant of &amp;ldquo;primitive&amp;rdquo; New Guinea tribe living in large Victorian house, and maintaining or adapting their tribal customs amid London life, a process studied and shared by their protector, a female anthropologist. One of their number is killed, and Pibble — intelligent, unassertive, tends to get assigned to off-beat cases that will bring no one any kudos — investigates.
Author Comment &amp;ldquo;The Glass-sided Ants&amp;rsquo; Nest&amp;rdquo; was the working title right up to late proof stage, when an elderly partner at my UK publishers wandered into the editorial offices, picked up a cover proof and said &amp;ldquo;You know, no woman will buy a book with an insect in the title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lizard in the Cup</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/lizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/lizard/</guid>
      <description>About the book Thanassi Thanatos (the tycoon first met in Sleep and his Brother) invites Pibble to Greek Island hideout to play role of Mafia in war-game style simulation of business opponents&amp;rsquo; likely actions. Pibble suggests elimination of Thanatos himself and then investigates the possibility for real. That’s why Jimmy Pibble joins five other men and a beautiful girl around a conference table in a lavish Mediterranean villa.
But what have two drunken Greek monks to do with murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Old English Peep Show(A Pride of Heroes)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/oepeepshow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/oepeepshow/</guid>
      <description>About the book Pibble investigates the apparent suicide of a servant in great English country house being run as a theme park, complete with lions, by two retired WWII heroes.
Author Comment A baroque spoof — I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine how I thought I could get away with it, but it won the CWA Golden Dagger.
Awards Crime Writers Association Golden Dagger (Winner) - 1969
Reviews  A literary magician. Sunday Telegraph  This is a bit crazy, harrowingly suspenseful, surprising - and different…not to be missed, if the offbeat appeals to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sinful Stones (The Seals)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sinfulstones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sinfulstones/</guid>
      <description>About the book James Pibble has been summoned to a remote Scottish island by his long-dead father&amp;rsquo;s ex-employer, the semi-senile Nobel Prize-winner, Sir Francis Francis. Before long, he finds himself attempting to extract Sir Francis from the grip of a crazed millenarian sect which seems determined to keep him there. It seems they will stop at nothing to make sure he stays. Including murder&amp;hellip;
Reviews  Fantastically inventive…a story full of imaginative detail with a stirring, sardonic end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Yellow Room Conspiracy</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/yellowroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/yellowroom/</guid>
      <description>About the book Two ex-lovers, he merely getting old, she already slowly dying, hear a radio quiz programme about a political/financial/sexual scandal in which they were both involved at the time of the Suez Crisis. At the end of the first chapter she asks him to tell her how he killed one of the other participants. He replies that he&amp;rsquo;d always imagined she had done it. Who then did?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>