<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Children&#39;s Books on Peter Dickinson Books</title>
    <link>http://peterdickinson.com/categories/childrens-book/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Children&#39;s Books on Peter Dickinson Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="http://peterdickinson.com/categories/childrens-book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Heartsease</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</guid>
      <description>About the Book England changes, machines become wicked and people dangerous. Heartsease is the second of Peter Dickinson’s “Changes” trilogy. (The Devil’s Children tells how this strange era began, and The Weathermonger how it ended.) Three children in a Cotswold village rescue a “witch”, nurse him and smuggle him to safety, with the help of a heroic pony and the ancient tug that gives the book its title.
This is a story of desperate adventuring in a world where every adult may be an enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weathermonger</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-book&#34;&gt;About the Book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a Britain returned to a medieval way of life following the &amp;ldquo;Changes&amp;rdquo;, which turned people against machines and electricity, Geoffrey, the local Weathermonger (chosen for his ability to summon rain when the farmers need it) and his sister are about to be drowned as &amp;ldquo;witches&amp;rdquo; for breaking the rules and maintaining an outboard engine. Following a thrilling escape to France (which has been unaffected by the Changes which have gripped Britain), Geoffrey and Sally return on a mission to discover the source of The Changes. This was Peter&amp;rsquo;s first children&amp;rsquo;s book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reviews&#34;&gt;Reviews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;A funny, fascinating and, at times, almost breathtaking web of adventure . . A first class, really stylish story.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;Punch&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;Since the Changes began, machines have been anathema in England except somehow, to Geoffrey Tinker . . . ingeniously conceived and vividly personalized.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;Kirkus - starred review&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publishers&#34;&gt;Publishers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gollancz, UK - 1968&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little Brown, US - 1969&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puffin Books, UK - 1970&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harlow Longman, UK - 1971&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delacorte Press, US - 1986&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dell, US - 1988&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collins Voyager, UK - 2003&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>