<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Children&#39;s Books on Peter Dickinson Books</title>
    <link>http://peterdickinson.com/categories/childrens-books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Children&#39;s Books on Peter Dickinson Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://peterdickinson.com/categories/childrens-books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emma Tupper&#39;s Diary</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/emmatupper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/emmatupper/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Sensible Emma Tupper stays with her wild Scots cousins, in whose private loch there is rumoured to be a monster. They also own the duplicate of one of the earliest submarines, in which they discover the reality behind the rumours, and then have to decide whether to exploit their find or conceal it and protect its precarious existence.
Author Comment For some reason this was great fun to write, and I&amp;rsquo;m told that comes through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heartsease</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</guid>
      <description>About the Book England changes, machines become wicked and people dangerous. Heartsease is the second of Peter Dickinson’s “Changes” trilogy. (The Devil’s Children tells how this strange era began, and The Weathermonger how it ended.) Three children in a Cotswold village rescue a “witch”, nurse him and smuggle him to safety, with the help of a heroic pony and the ancient tug that gives the book its title.
This is a story of desperate adventuring in a world where every adult may be an enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dancing Bear</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/dancingbear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/dancingbear/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Historical. Byzantine slave boy journeys into Hun territory to rescue captured daughter of the house, taking the trained household bear with him to act as a kind of passport (everyone would welcome the entertainment provided by a dancing bear) as he moves from the dangerous complexities of the city into the equally dangerous simplicities of the nomad Huns.
Author Comment This was the first of my books to evolve from a story I&amp;rsquo;d told my sons to stop them squabbling in the back seat during our weekly commute to and from Hampshire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Devil&#39;s Children</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/devilschildren/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/devilschildren/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Twelve-year old Nicola lost her parents when the mysterious Changes started turning people against machines. Lost and abandoned in the chaos which follows, Nicky meets a group of Sikhs, who are not affected by the Changes, and travels with them to try and find a safe place to live.
Awards Carnegie Medal (Commended) - 1970
Publishers Gollancz, UK - 1970
Atlantic-Little Brown, US - 1970
Puffin, UK - 1974</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weathermonger</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</guid>
      <description>About the Book In a Britain returned to a medieval way of life following the &amp;ldquo;Changes&amp;rdquo;, which turned people against machines and electricity, Geoffrey, the local Weathermonger (chosen for his ability to summon rain when the farmers need it) and his sister are about to be drowned as &amp;ldquo;witches&amp;rdquo; for breaking the rules and maintaining an outboard engine. Following a thrilling escape to France (which has been unaffected by the Changes which have gripped Britain), Geoffrey and Sally return on a mission to discover the source of The Changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>