<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Peter on Peter Dickinson Books</title>
    <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Peter on Peter Dickinson Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="http://peterdickinson.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 1</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;memories-of-peter-1&#34;&gt;Memories of Peter (1)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter’s brother, Hugh, shared the following memories of Peter’s childhood at
the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My earliest memories of Peter are when he was four years old, in our tropical
bungalow in Livingstone (now Zambia)—within sight of the plume of spray from
the Victoria Falls. We each had an African minder and a pet: Richard a sulky
eagle owl chained to a stump; Pete a mongoose which nipped our heels but was
meant to deter snakes (Dickie, our Dad, named it Ricki-Ticki-Tavi after
Kipling); I had an armadillo which was singularly unresponsive to affectionate
stroking. We bathed in the Zambezi protected from crocodiles by wire mesh
fencing and had picnics in the dry season on a rock right on the lip of the
Falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard and Peter swimming, 1932&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of travelling. We travelled to and fro—a gruelling three day
journey—to Plettenberg Bay on the South Coast of South Africa for the hot
weather and then to England (three week’s voyage in a Union Castle steamer) to
meet our English grandparents. We eventually settled as refugees in our
grandparents’ house in Painswick after our father died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a bit confused about the chronology but for several years we lodged with
our Hyett Great-Aunts in Painswick House, a small dowdy but beautiful Georgian
mansion in a huge wild garden with romantic Rococo follies half hidden in the
undergrowth. For Peter it was heaven. Aunt Lucy knew much of Shakespeare by
heart so there were yearly productions of Shakespeare on the Bowling Green in
which Peter always had a part. Julian Slade lived in the village so he was of
course the lead! There are many echoes of that lost world in Peter’s books. In
a production of Alice, Richard was the Mad Hatter; Peter the March Hare. I was
the Dormouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter and his brothers, 1937&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of Peter, my most vivid memory is of him sitting with his head in a book
anywhere he happened to be: on the stairs, under the billiard table, behind
the Library sofa; on any vacant bed, with his thumbs stuck in his ears to
exclude all exterior distractions like urgent calls. The only way to get his
attention was to grab the book and run. One winter evening he didn’t turn up
for lunch. We weren’t too surprised because time was a flexible dimension in
his world; but when it started to get dark our mother began to get worried and
I heard anxious grown-up whispered conversations:”What shall we do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it became too dark to read, the ten foot high double doors to the drawing
room were pushed open (the room was seldom used) and a rather bleary-eyed boy
came out to ask if it was lunch time yet. Our mother was uncharacteristically
cross with him—I think she had been really frightened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Peter, What have you been doing? We’ve been calling for you for hours!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, sorry Mum, just been finishing Macbeth and Hamlet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter, 1937&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had an extraordinary memory for poetry. At our prep school we had to
memorise a poem each week and recite it on demand. Peter learned Chesterton’s
“Lepanto“, admittedly in weekly chunks, but could still recite most of it
years later. I remember him chanting in a gale on Painswick Beacon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;White founts falling in the courts of the sun,
And the Soldan of Byzantium is smiling as they run;
There is laughter like the fountains in that face of all men feared,
It stirs the forest darkness, the darkness of his beard,
It curls the blood-red crescent, the crescent of his lips,
For the inmost sea of all the earth is shaken with his ships…
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugh, David, Nan &amp;amp; Peter, 1938&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mother loved Housman’s poems and used to recite them to us on our long
cross-country drives in our ancient Morris 8. Peter came to know many of them
by heart and as I sat beside his bed in the week before he died we recited
several together nudging each other’s memories. I have chosen the last poem he
spoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there Peter went to Eton as a King’s Scholar. It was a family tradition
of several generations that “going to school” simply meant going to Eton. He
was remarkably uncontaminated by the experience and seldom talked about it,
perhaps because he got terrible reports for idleness and carelessness, but his
natural intelligence got him an Exhibition to King’s College, Cambridge,
initially to read Classics but moving over to English as soon as he could. Our
ways gradually separated (I was spared the family tradition) but when we met
we always picked up our voluble conversations more or less at the point when
we had last left them. Richard used to complain that we talked simultaneously
and much too noisily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter at 18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did two years National Service in the Royal Signals—in the course of which
he managed to mislay four army trucks which were never traced. He told me that
a kindly Sergeant quartermaster added them to his own inventory of mislaid
equipment for which he was court-martialled. It sounds a bit like a novel. But
that is hardly surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final snippet. Peter loved limericks and invented a new verse form called
a ‘Bishopric’. There were strict rules: there had to be a Bishop in the first
line and another clerical office mentioned in the third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The Bishop of Joppa
Grew moss on his topper.
He said to his curate
“My wife will manure it,
I wish you could stop her.”

The Bishop of York
Ate his soup with a fork.
“My Lord,” said his vicar,
“A spoon would be quicker,
And allow us to talk.”

The Bishop of Bude
Used to bathe in the nude.
“My Lord,” said the Dean,
“Wear a hat, lest you’re seen
On the beach by a prude.”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was to Housman that his mind drifted back at the end. Tess is now going
to read one of his favourites which seems apt today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter’s niece, Hugh’s daughter, Tess, then read A.E. Housman‘s ‘Smooth Between
Sea and Land’.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Smooth between sea and land
Is laid the yellow sand,
And here through summer days
The seed of Adam plays.

Here the child comes to found
His unremaining mound,
And the grown lad to score
Two names upon the shore.

Here, on the level sand,
Between the sea and land,
What shall I build or write
Against the fall of night?

Tell me of runes to grave
That hold the bursting wave,
Or bastions to design
For longer date than mine.

Shall it be Troy or Rome
I fence against the foam,
Or my own name, to stay
When I depart for aye?

Nothing: too near at hand,
Planing the figure sand,
Effacing clean and fast
Cities not built to last
And charms devised in vain,
Pours the confounding main.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 2</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;memories-of-peter-2&#34;&gt;Memories of Peter (2)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter’s eldest daughter, Philippa, shared the following memories of Peter’s
early career at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there was Peter at King’s College, Cambridge. Dad, typically, said that he
felt he wasted his time there, worked ineffectually and took little part in
the many extra-curricular activities on offer. He didn’t get the hoped-for
first in his finals, but even so, the college gave him a bursary to study for
a PhD. Half way through this he walked into the Dean’s room. The Dean looked
up from the letter he was reading and asked, “Would you like a job on Punch?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The background to that story was that when the youngest member of the
five-strong editorial staff of the satirical magazine Punch turned 40, they
decided that they were getting too old and needed to get some younger blood in
to keep them relevant. The editor wrote to a don he knew at Cambridge to ask
him to find someone to train up. Allegedly someone else also wrote to a don at
Oxford who never replied. So Peter was the only candidate. On his way to the
interview for the job he was knocked down by a tram and arrived covered with
blood and dirt, but they gave him the job anyway. It makes a great first job
story and eventually made its way into his novel, Death of a Unicorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter at Punch 1953-58&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time, Peter went to a party in a friend’s rooms at King’s College,
Cambridge and met my mother, Mary-Rose. A pretty girl, standing by the
fireplace laughing delightedly because she had just managed to break an
unbreakable glass in the grate. Family legend then goes that soon after they
met, she was whisked away to India (allegedly because my grandparents did not
approve) and he thought he’d lost her forever. Almost a year passed – and Dad
was at another party when she came up behind him and rapped him on the
shoulder with her fan – he turned around and there was the girl of his dreams.
They were married at Bramdean, Hampshire, on April 26th 1953.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter and Mary-Rose wedding 1953&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter and Mary-Rose set up house in a flat in Pimlico, he continuing at Punch;
Mary-Rose working in the display department of Heal’s furniture store. A
couple of years later, I came along, followed by Polly the following year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They then moved to a seedy area of West London called Holland Park and set
about converting a tall, thin terraced house into a single family home (in
common with all the other houses in that street, it had been let as single
rooms with coin-operated gas fires). The pub over the road was a favourite
haunt for local workers and Friday nights were frequently enlivened by fights
in the street. Occasionally accompanied by a drunken fiddler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They did as much of the conversion of the house as they could themselves. Dad
made cupboards &amp;amp; shelves and created ingeniously designed tables and benches
to fit small spaces. Many of our childhood memories include laying slabs,
bricklaying, painting &amp;amp; decorating in every house we occupied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter laying garden slabs with the girls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile at Punch, Dad was progressing through a number of editorial
upheavals and jobs. At various points he was Art Editor (despite only being
able to draw trains sideways and dragons), resident poet, Literary Editor and
eventually Deputy Editor. It was clearly an extraordinary place to work
(occasionally the editorial team played cricket in the corridors) and brought
him into contact with some of the great humorists and cartoonists of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, the family was growing, with the arrival of John and James. My
parents bought a couple of small ramshackle cottages on the outskirts of the
village of Crondall, Hampshire and set about converting them into a single
dwelling. With a well, a chalk heap, a growing vegetable garden and wonderful
views, this was a great weekend and holiday home – and also eventually became
the setting for The Devils’ Children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter &amp;amp; children in the garden at Crondall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the most abiding memories I have of my father from this time are the
stories. He would read to us every night without fail and every car journey
there would be a new episode of a story to listen to. As I think back, I
realise how extraordinary this was but at the time, we just took it as normal.
Sometimes they were retellings of great legends –with a twist, perhaps. More
often they would be completely new. The boys always wanted a battle, so there
were lots of those. It was a brilliant way to keep four lively kids quiet on
long car journeys. He was our in-car entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter reading to the boys at bedtime&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time Peter started tinkering with what he believed to be an
original idea for a crime novel, working on the kitchen table after supper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1965 Peter and Mary-Rose moved from their cottage to take over half her
parent’s house at Bramdean, which must have been a huge stretch on a
journalist’s wages. It was a wonderful place in summer – though freezing cold
with a leaky roof in the winter. They developed a large vegetable garden and
Dad started brewing beer (more successful than his efforts at wine making!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter on bicycle at Bramdean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 1966-7ish Dad realised that the crime novel he was writing was completely
stuck. That must have been a bad time. But it also brought him the cold-sweat
nightmare which became the first scene of The Weathermonger. The following
evening, he put the crime novel aside and poured his heart into writing his
first children’s novel. Once that was done and on the way to his publisher, he
returned to the crime novel, saw pretty much instantly what he needed to do
with it and finished The Glass-Sided Ants Nest (published as Skin Deep in the
UK allegedly because someone at the publisher declared that no woman would
ever buy a book with an insect in the title).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1968 both The Weathermonger and The Glass-Sided Ant’s Nest were published to
great reviews. By that time he had completed two more novels and was starting
on a fifth. With these successes under his belt, he had what my maternal
grandfather described in his diary as ‘a sudden rush of blood to the head’,
left his job at Punch to become a full-time author – and also bought the other
half of the house at Bramdean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother, James is now going to read the opening scene to &lt;em&gt;The
Weathermonger&lt;/em&gt; – the nightmare which started it all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 3</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;memories-of-peter-3&#34;&gt;Memories of Peter (3)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter’s eldest son, John, shared the following memories of Peter’s blossoming
career as a writer at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for this next piece I need you to imagine that I’m voicing over the sound
of a typewriter. It’s coming from up a stairway or behind a study door, and it
sounds like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chack-chack-chack-chak. (Pause for thought.) Chackchackchackchackchackchack…
Peter typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter typing 1970s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter did not have typist’s hands. He said his fingers were like a sculptors,
thick and stubby. He typed from the elbow, two fingers, hitting the keys so
hard that he could break in ways that the repair people had never seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wrote books, but not only books. He wrote scripts for plays: amateur
productions that we performed with our friends the Stuart-Smiths at their
house at Serge Hill; and for the highly-talented children’s opera group who
performed in St James’ Church in London W11. He wrote a screenplay for a TV
series called Mandog, and drove our little Morris Minor as an extra in one of
the chase scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Like This, Like That’ W11 Children’s Opera&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he wrote poems. When he was re-roofing our large and leaky house at
Bramdean, he wrote poems about it on slates and hid them under the tiles for
future generations to find. He wrote a clutch of painful little poems after
the tragic death of Mary Rose in 1988, and more when Robin crossed the
Atlantic to join her life with his. Many of these are in his collection The
Weir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But his books were the main thing. He would write two a year, one adult
mystery, one children’s fiction, like a farmer rotating the crop in his field.
Often he’d start with just an idea, and no notion of where it would take him.
He said he could write a third of a murder novel without knowing who had
killed whom or why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter at a Puffin event for ‘The Changes’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His imagination was bold, far-reaching and quirky. He would follow a story set
in a Scottish Loch with one in sixth century Byzantium. He wrote about the
near future and also about the dawn of humanity. He did light romance in the
General Strike and science fiction in an apartheid Britain where skins were
green. He loved to set his stories in country houses like this one. And if
when you’re looking around you see a drop of fresh oil on a weapon in a
display case – that’s the clue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His characters were complex, his prose rhythmic, his ideas tantalising. He
would do nothing obvious or cheap. For him, all worthwhile moral questions
were complex and ambivalent. But he did not want to lecture his readers. He
took them round the byways, through the wild woods of imagination, and if they
came to ask themselves the sort of questions that he was asking – as it were,
by accident – that was all he could hope for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter’s ‘Puffin Passport’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He kept it up, for over sixty novels. That’s a gravity-defying career by all
standards. They’re all still available – just go to Openroad.com, or find his
website. Some of them won prizes. Tulku and City of Gold won the Carnegie in
consecutive years. Others did not, but his quality was always high. Have you
tried The Last Houseparty? Ah, you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carnegie Medal 2001 shortlist for ‘The Ropemaker’ with authors Eva Ibbotson
and Elizabeth Laird (also Marion Lloyd and Alyx Price from Macmillan)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil and Polly remember accompanying him to Crime Writers’ Association dinners
and rubbing shoulders with the greats like Harry Keating and Dick Francis.
James and I remember our excitement when he fell into a correspondence with
Richard Adams (I think Peter was less than excited about this, actually). He
served as Chair of the Society of Authors. He went on lecture tours, he was
awarded the O.B.E. for services to literature. But he was no highbrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He won prizes, he said, because his books were the sort that adults thought
children ought to read. He was ambivalent about that. He told an Exeter
conference in 1970 that the danger of living in a golden age of children’s
literature was that “not enough rubbish is being produced.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Nobody who has not spent a whole sunny afternoon under his bed rereading
a pile of comics left over from the previous holidays has any real idea of
the meaning of intellectual freedom.”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then that was fighting talk, and he had to defend it. Which he did. It
wasn’t in his commercial interest, but it was what he believed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter author tour 1970s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we thought we’d give you a bit of Peter’ essay “A Defence of Rubbish”. Here
he is, the writer’s writer, the librarian’s favourite, up and fighting for
children to be allowed what the hell they liked, even if, to the adult eye, it
contained no value either aesthetic or educational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John’s son, George, Peter’s grandson, then read the following passage from A
Defence of Rubbish…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“…Third, I am convinced of the importance of children discovering things
for themselves. However tactfully an adult may push them towards
discoveries in literature, these do not have quite the treasure trove
value of the books picked up wholly by accident. This can only be done by
random sampling on the part of the children, and it is inevitable that a
high proportion of what they read will be rubbish, by any standard. But in
the process they will learn the art of comparison.

Fourth comes a psychological point. Children have a very varying need of
security, but almost all children feel the need of security and
reassurance some time. One can often tell how happy or insecure a child is
feeling simply by what she is reading. And sometimes she may need to reread
something well known but which makes absolutely no intellectual or
emotional demand. Rubbish has this negative virtue, and I would be very
chary of interfering with a child who felt an obvious need of rubbish.

My fifth point is more nebulous. There is no proof, or even arguing about
it. But I am fairly sure in my own mind that a diet of plums is bad for
you, and that any rational reading system needs to include a considerable
amount of pap or roughage—call it what you will. I know very few adults
who do not have some secret cultural vice, and they are all the better for
it. I would instantly suspect an adult all of whose cultural activities
were high, remote and perfect.”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to take the podium again to make my confession here. I spent a fair
amount of my childhood re-reading football comics. I was probably aware that I
was being allowed to get away with it. I had no idea at all that I owed it to
his faith in intellectual freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books, Peter said, are like leaves. They fall from the tree that made them and
for a little while they lie golden on the ground. But very soon they are
buried by the next layer of books, which of course are doomed to be buried in
their turn. It’s a melancholy but realistic reflection on how much of a
monument a writer can expect from his own works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course, the monument is not really in the book at all. It’s in the
readers who found that treasure trove and were touched by what was in it. Even
if they can no longer remember the title or the author’s name. And sometimes
they do. A few years ago I met a young writer who said: ‘Peter Dickinson? We
had one of his books in the school library when I was twelve. It was called
The Gift. I loved it.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gift. Ah yes. Thank you, Peter. For that one too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are going to ask his wife and fellow writer Robin to take us into the
home and tell us a bit more of the man himself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes about Peter</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/quotes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;children-s-books&#34;&gt;Children&amp;rsquo;s Books&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;One of the real masters of children&#39;s literature.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;Peter Dickinson is a national treasure.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;The Guardian&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;Unfailingly erudite and inventive, he possesses an intriguing and unpredictable imagination.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;Independent&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;adult-novels&#34;&gt;Adult Novels&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;He is the true original, a superb writer who revitalises the traditions of the mystery genre . . . incapable of writing a trite or inelegant sentence . . . a master.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;P.D.James&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;The Tolkien of the crime novel.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;H.R.F.Keating&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;He sets new standards in the mystery field that will be hard to live up to.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;Ruth Rendell&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;He has an eye and a mind and a voice like no other.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;Donald E. Westlake&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;A stylist of subtle brilliance&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;I think Peter Dickinson is hands down the best stylist as a writer and the most interesting storyteller in my genre.&lt;/q&gt;

&lt;cite&gt;Sara Paretsky&lt;/cite&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>