<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Peter on Peter Dickinson Books</title>
    <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Peter on Peter Dickinson Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://peterdickinson.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 1</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-1/</guid>
      <description>Memories of Peter (1) Peter’s brother, Hugh, shared the following memories of Peter’s childhood at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:
My earliest memories of Peter are when he was four years old, in our tropical bungalow in Livingstone (now Zambia)—within sight of the plume of spray from the Victoria Falls. We each had an African minder and a pet: Richard a sulky eagle owl chained to a stump; Pete a mongoose which nipped our heels but was meant to deter snakes (Dickie, our Dad, named it Ricki-Ticki-Tavi after Kipling); I had an armadillo which was singularly unresponsive to affectionate stroking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 2</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-2/</guid>
      <description>Memories of Peter (2) Peter’s eldest daughter, Philippa, shared the following memories of Peter’s early career at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:
So there was Peter at King’s College, Cambridge. Dad, typically, said that he felt he wasted his time there, worked ineffectually and took little part in the many extra-curricular activities on offer. He didn’t get the hoped-for first in his finals, but even so, the college gave him a bursary to study for a PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 3</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-3/</guid>
      <description>Memories of Peter (3) Peter’s eldest son, John, shared the following memories of Peter’s blossoming career as a writer at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:
Now, for this next piece I need you to imagine that I’m voicing over the sound of a typewriter. It’s coming from up a stairway or behind a study door, and it sounds like this:
Chack-chack-chack-chak. (Pause for thought.) Chackchackchackchackchackchack… Peter typing
Peter typing 1970s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes about Peter</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Children&amp;rsquo;s Books  One of the real masters of children&#39;s literature. Philip Pullman  Peter Dickinson is a national treasure. The Guardian  Unfailingly erudite and inventive, he possesses an intriguing and unpredictable imagination. Independent Adult Novels  He is the true original, a superb writer who revitalises the traditions of the mystery genre . . . incapable of writing a trite or inelegant sentence . . . a master.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>