<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peter Dickinson Books</title>
    <link>http://peterdickinson.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Peter Dickinson Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://peterdickinson.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep and His Brother</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sleepandbrother/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sleepandbrother/</guid>
      <description>About the book Pibble, retired, involves himself in home for children suffering from rare disease (symptoms before early death include apparent telepathic powers), lavishly funded for ESP research by Greek tycoon. There&amp;rsquo;s an apparently accidental death in a fire, which Pibble noses into.
Reviews Brilliantly original, as always.Times Literary SupplementAn excellently engineered story.H.R. F. Keating, The TimesThe writing, as always, has style, and the setting…is full of invention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Glass-Sided Ants’ Nest (Skin Deep)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/the-glass-sided-ants-nest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/the-glass-sided-ants-nest/</guid>
      <description>About the book Set in Notting Dale, West London; remnant of &amp;ldquo;primitive&amp;rdquo; New Guinea tribe living in large Victorian house, and maintaining or adapting their tribal customs amid London life, a process studied and shared by their protector, a female anthropologist. One of their number is killed, and Pibble — intelligent, unassertive, tends to get assigned to off-beat cases that will bring no one any kudos — investigates.
Author Comment &amp;ldquo;The Glass-sided Ants&amp;rsquo; Nest&amp;rdquo; was the working title right up to late proof stage, when an elderly partner at my UK publishers wandered into the editorial offices, picked up a cover proof and said &amp;ldquo;You know, no woman will buy a book with an insect in the title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lizard in the Cup</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/lizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/lizard/</guid>
      <description>About the book Thanassi Thanatos (the tycoon first met in Sleep and his Brother) invites Pibble to Greek Island hideout to play role of Mafia in war-game style simulation of business opponents&amp;rsquo; likely actions. Pibble suggests elimination of Thanatos himself and then investigates the possibility for real. That’s why Jimmy Pibble joins five other men and a beautiful girl around a conference table in a lavish Mediterranean villa.
But what have two drunken Greek monks to do with murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Old English Peep Show(A Pride of Heroes)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/oepeepshow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/oepeepshow/</guid>
      <description>About the book Pibble investigates the apparent suicide of a servant in great English country house being run as a theme park, complete with lions, by two retired WWII heroes.
Author Comment A baroque spoof — I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine how I thought I could get away with it, but it won the CWA Golden Dagger.
Awards Crime Writers Association Golden Dagger (Winner) - 1969
Reviews A literary magician.Sunday TelegraphThis is a bit crazy, harrowingly suspenseful, surprising - and different…not to be missed, if the offbeat appeals to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sinful Stones (The Seals)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sinfulstones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sinfulstones/</guid>
      <description>About the book James Pibble has been summoned to a remote Scottish island by his long-dead father&amp;rsquo;s ex-employer, the semi-senile Nobel Prize-winner, Sir Francis Francis. Before long, he finds himself attempting to extract Sir Francis from the grip of a crazed millenarian sect which seems determined to keep him there. It seems they will stop at nothing to make sure he stays. Including murder&amp;hellip;
Reviews Fantastically inventive…a story full of imaginative detail with a stirring, sardonic end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emma Tupper&#39;s Diary</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/emmatupper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/emmatupper/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Sensible Emma Tupper stays with her wild Scots cousins, in whose private loch there is rumoured to be a monster. They also own the duplicate of one of the earliest submarines, in which they discover the reality behind the rumours, and then have to decide whether to exploit their find or conceal it and protect its precarious existence.
Author Comment For some reason this was great fun to write, and I&amp;rsquo;m told that comes through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heartsease</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</guid>
      <description>About the Book England changes, machines become wicked and people dangerous. Heartsease is the second of Peter Dickinson’s “Changes” trilogy. (The Devil’s Children tells how this strange era began, and The Weathermonger how it ended.) Three children in a Cotswold village rescue a “witch”, nurse him and smuggle him to safety, with the help of a heroic pony and the ancient tug that gives the book its title.
This is a story of desperate adventuring in a world where every adult may be an enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dancing Bear</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/dancingbear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/dancingbear/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Historical. Byzantine slave boy journeys into Hun territory to rescue captured daughter of the house, taking the trained household bear with him to act as a kind of passport (everyone would welcome the entertainment provided by a dancing bear) as he moves from the dangerous complexities of the city into the equally dangerous simplicities of the nomad Huns.
Author Comment This was the first of my books to evolve from a story I&amp;rsquo;d told my sons to stop them squabbling in the back seat during our weekly commute to and from Hampshire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Devil&#39;s Children</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/devilschildren/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/devilschildren/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Twelve-year old Nicola lost her parents when the mysterious Changes started turning people against machines. Lost and abandoned in the chaos which follows, Nicky meets a group of Sikhs, who are not affected by the Changes, and travels with them to try and find a safe place to live.
Awards Carnegie Medal (Commended) - 1970
Publishers Gollancz, UK - 1970
Atlantic-Little Brown, US - 1970
Puffin, UK - 1974</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weathermonger</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</guid>
      <description>About the Book In a Britain returned to a medieval way of life following the &amp;ldquo;Changes&amp;rdquo;, which turned people against machines and electricity, Geoffrey, the local Weathermonger (chosen for his ability to summon rain when the farmers need it) and his sister are about to be drowned as &amp;ldquo;witches&amp;rdquo; for breaking the rules and maintaining an outboard engine. Following a thrilling escape to France (which has been unaffected by the Changes which have gripped Britain), Geoffrey and Sally return on a mission to discover the source of The Changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/404/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books that Mattered to me When Young</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books-that-mattered-to-me-when-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books-that-mattered-to-me-when-young/</guid>
      <description>Books that Mattered to me When Young St George for England by G.A. Henty
I came across a copy of this not long ago and was astonished to find how bad it is, mostly undigested chunks of history about the Hundred Years’ War, with our hero popping up from time to time to have an adventure. Early on he rescues the girl who becomes his childhood sweetheart. You don’t hear about her again till near the end, when you find he’s married to her, and gets to rescue her again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/faq/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions Note If you’re upon a School Assignment You won’t be wanting this refinement. Cheer up! There’s stuff about each book Elsewhere, if you would care to look.  Do you put people you know into your books? Where was she from, the woman in the tower? I pushed a doorway on the winding stair, Stole hesitantly in, and she was there, An absolute presence, filling the room with power, Her life a moment in my sleeping brain — I know her, though we never meet again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 1</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-1/</guid>
      <description>Memories of Peter (1) Peter’s brother, Hugh, shared the following memories of Peter’s childhood at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:
My earliest memories of Peter are when he was four years old, in our tropical bungalow in Livingstone (now Zambia)—within sight of the plume of spray from the Victoria Falls. We each had an African minder and a pet: Richard a sulky eagle owl chained to a stump; Pete a mongoose which nipped our heels but was meant to deter snakes (Dickie, our Dad, named it Ricki-Ticki-Tavi after Kipling); I had an armadillo which was singularly unresponsive to affectionate stroking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 2</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-2/</guid>
      <description>Memories of Peter (2) Peter’s eldest daughter, Philippa, shared the following memories of Peter’s early career at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:
So there was Peter at King’s College, Cambridge. Dad, typically, said that he felt he wasted his time there, worked ineffectually and took little part in the many extra-curricular activities on offer. He didn’t get the hoped-for first in his finals, but even so, the college gave him a bursary to study for a PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memories of Peter 3</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/memories-of-peter-3/</guid>
      <description>Memories of Peter (3) Peter’s eldest son, John, shared the following memories of Peter’s blossoming career as a writer at the memorial on 6 Jan 2016:
Now, for this next piece I need you to imagine that I’m voicing over the sound of a typewriter. It’s coming from up a stairway or behind a study door, and it sounds like this:
Chack-chack-chack-chak. (Pause for thought.) Chackchackchackchackchackchack… Peter typing
Peter typing 1970s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Peter</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/my-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/my-peter/</guid>
      <description>My Peter Peter’s wife, Robin McKinley, gave this moving tribute at his memorial in January 2016. This text was first published on Robin’s blog.
Peter’s first romantic fiancé’s gift to me was a pair of secateurs. This was about four hours after he’d said ‘just because you’re taking me on doesn’t mean you have to take gardening on.’ I was in England seeing what I was getting myself into. Peter and I had had an unexpectedly life-altering weekend in Maine about a fortnight before; we knew each other slightly through the book world, I’d visited him at home once when Mary Rose was still alive, he was merely returning the favour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Novels</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/writing/writing-novels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/writing/writing-novels/</guid>
      <description>On Writing Novels I have always taken writing for children and writing for adults equally seriously, but my relationship with the adult novels is different, more willed, less “given”. There are of course repetitive themes. My children say that my definitive novel will be about a chimpanzee trying to support a great country house by writing best-sellers.
I was brought up as one of the impoverished gentry, but despite a patrician accent and manner have never felt confident that I belonged in my supposed class; and I spent formative parts of my adolescence in a big Georgian house where my two old cousins were struggling on inadequate funds to keep things going in order to be able to hand it on to the heir to whom it was entailed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes about Peter</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/about/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/about/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Children&amp;rsquo;s Books One of the real masters of children&#39;s literature.Philip PullmanPeter Dickinson is a national treasure.The GuardianUnfailingly erudite and inventive, he possesses an intriguing and unpredictable imagination.IndependentAdult Novels He is the true original, a superb writer who revitalises the traditions of the mystery genre . . . incapable of writing a trite or inelegant sentence . . . a master.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>