<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peter Dickinson Books</title>
    <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Peter Dickinson Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://peterdickinson.com/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One Foot in the Grave</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/onefoot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/onefoot/</guid>
      <description>About the book A coda to the Pibble series. Pibble is in a nursing home, prematurely feeble and despairing. To put an end to it by dying of hypothermia, he slips out one bitter winter&amp;rsquo;s night and climbs to the top of the water tower, only to find that the place he had chosen is already occupied by the dead body of another. Duty drives him to return and report it, and then, inexorably, he finds himself forced to unravel, from his sick-bed and through the come-and-go of delirium, what happened, and why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep and His Brother</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sleepandbrother/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sleepandbrother/</guid>
      <description>About the book Pibble, retired, involves himself in home for children suffering from rare disease (symptoms before early death include apparent telepathic powers), lavishly funded for ESP research by Greek tycoon. There&amp;rsquo;s an apparently accidental death in a fire, which Pibble noses into.
Reviews Brilliantly original, as always.Times Literary SupplementAn excellently engineered story.H.R. F. Keating, The TimesThe writing, as always, has style, and the setting…is full of invention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Glass-Sided Ants’ Nest (Skin Deep)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/the-glass-sided-ants-nest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/the-glass-sided-ants-nest/</guid>
      <description>About the book Set in Notting Dale, West London; remnant of &amp;ldquo;primitive&amp;rdquo; New Guinea tribe living in large Victorian house, and maintaining or adapting their tribal customs amid London life, a process studied and shared by their protector, a female anthropologist. One of their number is killed, and Pibble — intelligent, unassertive, tends to get assigned to off-beat cases that will bring no one any kudos — investigates.
Author Comment &amp;ldquo;The Glass-sided Ants&amp;rsquo; Nest&amp;rdquo; was the working title right up to late proof stage, when an elderly partner at my UK publishers wandered into the editorial offices, picked up a cover proof and said &amp;ldquo;You know, no woman will buy a book with an insect in the title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Green Gene</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/greengene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/greengene/</guid>
      <description>About the book An attempt to imagine for the British what Verwoerd-style apartheid would be like if applied here, and people of Celtic origin had green skins. P.P. Humayan, a naive Indian mathematical genius, is hired by UK racial police to do statistical analysis on likely increase of Green population. His hosts are murdered and he is kidnapped by and then becomes involved with a subversive Green movement.
Reviews Zany panache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lizard in the Cup</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/lizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/lizard/</guid>
      <description>About the book Thanassi Thanatos (the tycoon first met in Sleep and his Brother) invites Pibble to Greek Island hideout to play role of Mafia in war-game style simulation of business opponents&amp;rsquo; likely actions. Pibble suggests elimination of Thanatos himself and then investigates the possibility for real. That’s why Jimmy Pibble joins five other men and a beautiful girl around a conference table in a lavish Mediterranean villa.
But what have two drunken Greek monks to do with murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Old English Peep Show(A Pride of Heroes)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/oepeepshow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/oepeepshow/</guid>
      <description>About the book Pibble investigates the apparent suicide of a servant in great English country house being run as a theme park, complete with lions, by two retired WWII heroes.
Author Comment A baroque spoof — I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine how I thought I could get away with it, but it won the CWA Golden Dagger.
Awards Crime Writers Association Golden Dagger (Winner) - 1969
Reviews A literary magician.Sunday TelegraphThis is a bit crazy, harrowingly suspenseful, surprising - and different…not to be missed, if the offbeat appeals to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Poison Oracle</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/poisonoracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/poisonoracle/</guid>
      <description>About the book Oil-rich sheikh funds Morris, a wimpish psycholinguist, to continue researches into the language abilities of Morris&amp;rsquo;s chimp, Dinah, in his desert palace. The local marsh-people, not Arabs, have a uniquely complex language, which Morris is studying. By custom they provide the sheikh&amp;rsquo;s personal bodyguard. There is oil under the marshes, but its exploitation would break an ancient treaty with the marsh people. The sheikh is murdered, apparently by his bodyguard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sinful Stones (The Seals)</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sinfulstones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/sinfulstones/</guid>
      <description>About the book James Pibble has been summoned to a remote Scottish island by his long-dead father&amp;rsquo;s ex-employer, the semi-senile Nobel Prize-winner, Sir Francis Francis. Before long, he finds himself attempting to extract Sir Francis from the grip of a crazed millenarian sect which seems determined to keep him there. It seems they will stop at nothing to make sure he stays. Including murder&amp;hellip;
Reviews Fantastically inventive…a story full of imaginative detail with a stirring, sardonic end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Yellow Room Conspiracy</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/yellowroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 03:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/yellowroom/</guid>
      <description>About the book Two ex-lovers, he merely getting old, she already slowly dying, hear a radio quiz programme about a political/financial/sexual scandal in which they were both involved at the time of the Suez Crisis. At the end of the first chapter she asks him to tell her how he killed one of the other participants. He replies that he&amp;rsquo;d always imagined she had done it. Who then did?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emma Tupper&#39;s Diary</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/emmatupper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/emmatupper/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Sensible Emma Tupper stays with her wild Scots cousins, in whose private loch there is rumoured to be a monster. They also own the duplicate of one of the earliest submarines, in which they discover the reality behind the rumours, and then have to decide whether to exploit their find or conceal it and protect its precarious existence.
Author Comment For some reason this was great fun to write, and I&amp;rsquo;m told that comes through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heartsease</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/heartsease/</guid>
      <description>About the Book England changes, machines become wicked and people dangerous. Heartsease is the second of Peter Dickinson’s “Changes” trilogy. (The Devil’s Children tells how this strange era began, and The Weathermonger how it ended.) Three children in a Cotswold village rescue a “witch”, nurse him and smuggle him to safety, with the help of a heroic pony and the ancient tug that gives the book its title.
This is a story of desperate adventuring in a world where every adult may be an enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dancing Bear</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/dancingbear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/dancingbear/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Historical. Byzantine slave boy journeys into Hun territory to rescue captured daughter of the house, taking the trained household bear with him to act as a kind of passport (everyone would welcome the entertainment provided by a dancing bear) as he moves from the dangerous complexities of the city into the equally dangerous simplicities of the nomad Huns.
Author Comment This was the first of my books to evolve from a story I&amp;rsquo;d told my sons to stop them squabbling in the back seat during our weekly commute to and from Hampshire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Devil&#39;s Children</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/devilschildren/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/devilschildren/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Twelve-year old Nicola lost her parents when the mysterious Changes started turning people against machines. Lost and abandoned in the chaos which follows, Nicky meets a group of Sikhs, who are not affected by the Changes, and travels with them to try and find a safe place to live.
Awards Carnegie Medal (Commended) - 1970
Publishers Gollancz, UK - 1970
Atlantic-Little Brown, US - 1970
Puffin, UK - 1974</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gift</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/gift/</guid>
      <description>About the Book A Welsh boy with erratic telepathic powers finds himself in touch with the mind of violent criminal, with whom his irresponsible father is also somehow involved.
Author Comment This also evolved out of my schooldays. I read a fair amount of SF, and I&amp;rsquo;m usually impatient with the stories involving telepathy, because they make it sound useful and controllable, whereas my only probable telepathic experience convinces me that it&amp;rsquo;s neither.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Iron Lion</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/ironlion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/ironlion/</guid>
      <description>About the Book Persian-style fairy story about how the poorest prince in the world persuaded the Iron Lion of Ferdustan to help him win the hand of the Princess of Persia. Originally illustrated by Marc Brown, later by Pauline Baynes.
Author Comment This was the first of my own told-in-the-car stories — previously I&amp;rsquo;d told the kids versions of Snow White, Rapunzel, and so on. They now tell some of mine to their own children on long journeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weathermonger</title>
      <link>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 01:55:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://peterdickinson.com/books/weathermonger/</guid>
      <description>About the Book In a Britain returned to a medieval way of life following the &amp;ldquo;Changes&amp;rdquo;, which turned people against machines and electricity, Geoffrey, the local Weathermonger (chosen for his ability to summon rain when the farmers need it) and his sister are about to be drowned as &amp;ldquo;witches&amp;rdquo; for breaking the rules and maintaining an outboard engine. Following a thrilling escape to France (which has been unaffected by the Changes which have gripped Britain), Geoffrey and Sally return on a mission to discover the source of The Changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>